<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy Efficiency | Behnaz Bostanipour</title>
    <link>/tag/energy-efficiency/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/energy-efficiency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Energy Efficiency</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Energy Efficiency</title>
      <link>/tag/energy-efficiency/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstractions and Algorithms for Building Proximity-Based Mobile Applications in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks</title>
      <link>/project/phd-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/phd-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this thesis, I introduced a set of programming abstractions and algorithms that can be used for building Proximity-Based Mobile (PBM) applications in mobile ad hoc networks (MANETs). The PBM applications are emerging distributed applications which enable users of mobile devices such as smartphones to interact with other users in a defined range and for a certain time duration for different purposes such as social networking, dating, gaming, driving, etc. For all proposed algorithms in the thesis, I presented a proof of correctness. I also performed realistic simulation-based studies (using ns-2 simulator) to evaluate the performance of algorithms. For these simulations, I wrote programs in different languages such as C++, Java as well as OTCL/TCL and shell scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstractions and Algorithms for Building Proximity-Based Mobile Applications in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks</title>
      <link>/publication/phd-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/phd-thesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of an Energy Efficient Opportunistic Routing Protocol for Wireless Sensor Networks (for SensorScope project at EPFL)</title>
      <link>/project/sensorscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sensorscope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my internship at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epfl.ch/labs/lcav/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Audiovisual Communications Laboratory (LCAV)&lt;/a&gt;, I developed a singlepath routing protocol and an opportunistic anypath routing protocol in nesC (network embedded systems C)/TinyOS for &lt;a href=&#34;https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.1020.5816&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SensorScope project&lt;/a&gt;. I executed the two protocols on Tmote sensor motes and compared the results in terms of energy consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
